Scott James

152 Willow Road Dartford, DA1 2QP | Mobile: 07747 089443 email: scottaustinjames@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/ | GitHub: https://github.com/

Profile

I am a creative, self-motivated individual who is passionate about IT, I taught myself how to code while at college and have since gained a career with 5+ years of experience as a full stack developer creating web apps and websites for businesses with a proven increase on their overall online presence, I am now looking for migrating my skills and continue learning and adapting to new software and technologies.

Training and Education

TechTalent Academy, Cyber Academy

September 2022 - Ongoing

BCS Foundation Certificate Information Security Management Principles

Learndirect February 2016 – July 2016

Mathematics A English A

North West Kent College

September 2013 – July 2015

Pearson BTEC Level 3 Diploma in Professional Competence for IT and

Telecoms Professionals.

Pearson BTEC Level 2 Diploma in Professional Competence for IT and

Telecoms Professionals.

Pearson BTEC Level 2 in ICT Systems and Principles.

Skills

HTML & CSS JavaScript PHP
React SQL Adobe XD
WordPress Apache Server Database Management
Customer Relationship Management Active Directory Windows Server
(CRM)

Work experience

Freelance (Remote), Full Stack Developer

2017 - Present

- Managing client proposals from start to finish including during the design, print, and production processes.
- Developing a high level of expertise in programming languages such as HTML, PHP, and JavaScript coding.
- Ensuring the site is properly optimized for the search engines (SEO).
- Performing QA testing.
- Write and debug software code.
- Keeping up to date with modern design and developer trends.
- Strong problem-solving skills.
- Strong understanding of web development programming techniques and tools.

PC World (Crayford), Business Advisor

2016 - 2017

- Customer service and in-house customer service training.
- Marketing, presentation, and, promotional duties.
- Clerical duties (data entry, record-keeping, appointment scheduling, answering, and routing phone calls).
- Identifying potential business customers for future business development.
- Preparing financial reports and analysing consumer and competitor behaviour.
- business-to-business(B2B) and business-to-customer (B2C) sales.
- Up-selling to customers and businesses.
- Recognize and reach out to clients in businesses.
- Meeting daily, weekly, and monthly KPI.

North West Kent College, IT Technician

2013 - 2015

- Recording customer information with a CRM system.
- Installing and configuring the network, hardware, and software.
- Repair or replace damaged hardware.

- Troubleshooting network, hardware, and software issues and resolving all IT-related problems.
- Conduct backup activities and disaster preparedness.
- Instal and upgrade the computer network.
- Working with Microsoft server and active directory.

Interests & hobbies

Studying towards more IT qualifications, Security+, AWS cloud practitioner, CISMP, Cisco Network+ Game Development I am learning how to create video games in unity while also learning about C# Darts & Golf perfect sports for me to clear my head and I have met great people after playing in local tournaments.

Personal achievements

IT Army of Ukraine Cyber Specialist 2022, Wanting to help Ukraine and seeing websites hosted in Ukraine being attacked I joined the IT Army of Ukraine where I was given training material and resources to help fight back against Russian aggression. WebJam1 Winner 2021, Having one week to complete a website based upon the theme of nature, I decided to make a charity website for African elephants and the ivory trade winning me first place for my simplistic creative design.

Arctic Code Vault Contributor 2020, I am one of the lucky few who got their code preserved for future generations in GitHub arctic yault in the arctic mountains of Syalbard.

References

Available upon request